I thought with confidence that this
would be the year that I finally switch
over to a foldable phone. I've been
testing these things for like seven or
eight years, but I've never been drawn
to one the way that I've been drawn to
the Fold 7 because this is the first
product that's been like it it looks and
feels and has the weight and thickness
of a regular phone. It's just that when
you wanted to, you can open it up and
it's like a bigger screen experience in
a tablet-like device. And I've been
using this for 2 weeks. I thought for
sure this would be the one, but I just I
don't like it nearly as much as I
thought I would. So, in order to explain
where I'm coming from, we have to go
back a little bit and think about the
origins of why we even are so enamored
with foldable phones in the first place.
I think it just boils down to
versatility, right? We want a device
that can be a phone when we want it to
be and then a tablet for that big screen
experience when we want it to be. and
versatile tech. It's always so cool on
paper like a twoin- one tablet, right?
It's like the idea that you could have a
tablet and a laptop in one product. But
versatility also comes with the cost.
The cost of I'm not talking about price.
I'm talking about like you have
engineering compromises that you have to
make in order to have a multi-function
device. So in the two in one tablet, you
have a tablet experience that's not
perfect and you have a laptop experience
that's not perfect, but you have a
versatile two in one product. And the
same thing has been the case with
foldable phones. You have a phone
experience that's typically not perfect
because it's like a little bit thicker
or whatever. And you also have a tablet
experience that's also imperfect because
like there's things you have to do to be
able to make it foldable. Now, on the
Fold 7 this year, I think Samsung made
the phone experience really good. like
as close as possible to like a regular
uh like slab phone because now it's like
the same weight and same dimensions as a
regular slab phone. But in doing so,
they had to make it really thin to do
that, right? In doing so, the tablet
experience is noticeably worse than it
was in previous generations. So, the
first thing, right when I opened it from
the box two weeks ago, I thought when I
first unboxed it, I'm like, "Huh, it's a
little bit harder to open than previous
generations." But I thought, you know,
it's a new product. Maybe my Fold six
has seen so much use that it got used to
it. But it's not the case. I think two
weeks later, it's just that the Fold
six, first of all, there's more material
to grip onto when you do open it. But
the hinge is just like it's just built
differently. It's like a nice easy open.
The Fold 7, for sure, this is a tougher
product to hold uh to open. You got to
you just got to work it. I'm surprised
they didn't add some kind of like ledge
or some kind of notch that you can work
to just crank it open, but there's less
material to open when it's so thin,
right? Also, when you do open it,
because it's so thin this year, we've
lost the S Pen functionality, which I
think disappointed a lot of people. We
don't have the underdis camera anymore.
We now have like the punch hole that's
always there. Uh the speakers are
noticeably worse this generation than
the previous. It's not like awful
speakers, but they were quite good on
the Fold 6 before. And we also have a
massive camera bump. This protrudes out
a lot and the image quality is better
this year, but to me that improvement in
image quality is so not worth the bulk
that this camera system has added. You
definitely need a case of some sort. The
wobble on this thing is pretty severe
and I don't know, it just sticks out so
much that I have a tough time calling
this phone really thin because the
hardware bump is no joke. But despite
all the quirks we've talked about,
fundamentally, Samsung brought out
something that was very impressive. The
hardware is amazing to be able to have a
phone that is actually super thin like
this but opens up into this big screen
experience. It's impressive. But we got
to talk about this whole big screen
experience because this is what
everyone's drawn to, right? The idea of
that big screen experience. So, right
off the bat, this screen is awesome for
like viewing documents and PDFs and like
reading ebooks. These are things that I
never do, but it is fantastic screen for
that. Uh now the other thing that
Samsung pushes is the idea of
multitasking. Like you get split screen
and floating windows for multi-app
workflows. The new software is awesome
for that. But again, these are things
that I don't really do. Like I thought I
would I thought I would at least at some
point make use of it, but it's just not
in my workflow. So I'm sure there's tons
of people that do make use of multi-app
workflows, like very productive, awesome
people, but I'm just I'm not that. I'm
like a degenerate that watches videos,
that looks at shorts. I look like I
browseed Reddit. I like message people
like it's a very different thing for
what I do compared to what we see in
Samsung's ads and I use it and I'm like
why am I not able to make use of this
multi-creen stuff like I just want a big
ass screen but the size of the videos
are not actually all that bigger than a
regular slap phone. It's always
disappointing that when I pop this thing
open there's so much wasted screen area
from the black bars. It does get better
if you rotate it but it's just not a
massive difference. The crease is still
there if you look for it. It doesn't
bother me at this point because I've
been staring at these creases for like
seven years. But at the same time, I've
shown this to my wife and she's like,
"That's awful. How can you sell a
product that looks like that?" She finds
it so distracting. So, obviously, this
is a very subjective thing. So, uh, you
know what? This whole video, everything
I'm saying, it's like an opinion that
spawns from me. It's my perspective
coming from someone who was very eager
to swap to a foldable this year because
like it seems so awesome on paper. But
if this somehow aligns with what you're
thinking and you're drawn to this phone
because they made such big leaps in
hardware this year, maybe this will help
you make a purchase decision. Now, I
think when I take a step back that one
of the main reasons why I just don't
love this phone, is still the aspect
ratio. If I compare this to like
foldables of the past, this is a much
older device. This is the Oppo Find N2,
I believe. This form factor, the more
book style, like the stouter book, I'm
so drawn to this. This has like that
form factor that just works so much
better with the type of stuff that I do.
When you pop it open, you have a screen
that has less wasted space when you're
watching videos. And I just like the
form factor of this a little bit more. I
really like the kind of just the shape
of that more stout book type feel. Now,
the rumors are that Apple is releasing a
foldable finally after all these years
that is supposed to line up with uh this
kind of form factor if that's something
that you want to keep in mind. And
supposedly the foldables next year will
have a tech that removes the crease.
Like there's supposed to be some kind of
flexible metal under layer that props up
that middle section to just hide that
crease, which would be really
interesting to see. But this whole
video, again, from the perspective from
me, I wanted to use this thing. I was
like so confident that this would be the
one. But I'm just not the type of person
that takes advantage of the multitasking
and just the utility of the inner screen
for what this form factor is really
designed for. Uh just as an anecdotal
like thought, when I've talked to some
of my peers in the YouTube reviewing
space, the tech reviewing space that so
few of us use foldables. Like over the
years, we've had access to so much stuff
that's come in. We've had like all the
incentives to try these things and just
and use them. But how many, if you think
about it, how many tech reviewers
actually use foldables as their as their
device? It's interesting when you think
about it. Okay. Uh, there you have it.
The Fold 7.